export const SOCIALSTUDIESA2006 = [

{
id: "question1",
question: "1. For peaceful co-existence and harmonious living of my group of people there is the need for a",
A: "constitution",
B: "court",
C: "leader",
D: "president",
answer: "C. leader",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question2",
question: "2. The key factor to the discovery and development of one’s capabilities is",
A: "availability of education",
B: "the desire of the individual",
C: "availability of financial resource",
D: "control of the environment.",
answer: "B. the desire of the individual",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question3",
question: "3. Legal rights are conferred on the citizen by",
A: "the United Nations Organization",
B: "Courts of law",
C: "Acts of Parliament",
D: "the constitution",
answer: "D. the constitution",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question4",
question: "4. Traditional rule is based on",
A: "dictatorship",
B: "consensus building",
C: "organized opposition",
D: "chieftaincy",
answer: "B. consensus building",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question5",
question: "5. Self-identity implies personal",
A: "physical appearance",
B: "acquisition of skills",
C: "heredity traits",
D: "awareness and consciousness",
answer: "D. awareness and consciousness",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question6",
question: "6. Polygynous marriage is permitted order  \nI.	Muslim marriage  \nII.	Ordinance marriage  \nIII.	Traditional marriage  \nIV.	Christian marriage",
A: "I and II only",
B: "I and III only",
C: "I and IV only",
D: "III and IV only",
answer: "B. I and III only",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question7",
question: "7. The most effective way to reduce teenage pregnancy in the society is to",
A: "involve girls in the family decision-making process",
B: "punish girls who become pregnant",
C: "assist the girls in looking for good husbands",
D: "keep girls in school for us long as possible",
answer: "A. involve girls in the family decision-making process",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question8",
question: "8. Primary socialization is the exclusive responsibility of the",
A: "extended family",
B: "nuclear family",
C: "church",
D: "school",
answer: "B. nuclear family",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question9",
question: "9. Widowhood rites are performed mainly to",
A: "appease the spirit of a dead spouse",
B: "avenge the death of a spouse",
C: "pacify the goods",
D: "sever spiritual relationship with the ancestors",
answer: "A. appease the spirit of a dead spouse",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question10",
question: "10. Which of the following bodies helps in the conservation of the environment?",
A: "The Meteorological Services Department",
B: "Ghana Atomic Energy Commission",
C: "The Forestry Commission",
D: "Ghana Standards Board",
answer: "C. The Forestry Commission",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question11",
question: "11. The best way a parent can help the child to live a sustainable life is to",
A: "open a savings account for the child",
B: "give the child good education",
C: "buy the child treasury bill",
D: "prepare a will for the child",
answer: "B. give the child good education",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question12",
question: "12. All the following are effects of the breakdown of marriage except",
A: "child delinquency",
B: "single parenting",
C: "broken homes",
D: "cessation of blood ties",
answer: "C. broken homes",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question13",
question: "13. Which of the following devices can be used to minimize air pollution in an industrial area?",
A: "Air freshener",
B: "Incinerator",
C: "Chimney",
D: "Turbine",
answer: "C. Chimney",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question14",
question: "14. Social deviants can best be reformed through",
A: "corporal punishment",
B: "banishment and isolation",
C: "guidance and counselling",
D: "detention and imprisonment",
answer: "C. guidance and counselling",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question15",
question: "15. If a population grows faster than the resources necessary to maintain the increasing numbers it results in growth in per capital income increase in foreign debt pressure on social amenities balance of payment deficit",
A: "**********",
B: "**********",
C: "**********",
D: "**********",
answer: "C. pressure on social amenities",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question16",
question: "16. National integration can be promoted by all the following except",
A: "common festivals",
B: "ethnic sentiments",
C: "inter-ethnic marriage",
D: "common festivals",
answer: "B. ethnic sentiments",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question17",
question: "17. When workers develop positive work ethics, it results in",
A: "the workers sharpening their skills",
B: "greater profits for the business",
C: "recruitment of more labour",
D: "less labour disputes",
answer: "B. greater profits for the business",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question18",
question: "18. Ghana’s membership of any international organization is ratified by the",
A: "Legislature",
B: "Judiciary",
C: "Executive",
D: "council of state",
answer: "A. Legislature",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question19",
question: "19. International economic co-operation is necessary due to the fact that countries",
A: "have abundant resources",
B: "are endowed with the same resources",
C: "have scarce resources",
D: "are differently endowed",
answer: "D. are differently endowed",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question20",
question: "20. In order to improve upon science education in Ghana, basic schools should be",
A: "staffed by only science teachers",
B: "supplied with adequate science equipment",
C: "made to teach only science subject",
D: "permitted to enroll only children who are above average",
answer: "B. supplied with adequate science equipment",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question21",
question: "21. The application of modern technology by the entrepreneur helps him to",
A: "increase the prices of his goods",
B: "employ more skilled personnel",
C: "reduce his cost of production",
D: "enjoy monopoly in production",
answer: "C. reduce his cost of production",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question22",
question: "22. The key factor to the exploitation of the abundant natural resources in Ghana is the",
A: "importation of machinery",
B: "payment of higher wages and salaries",
C: "establishment of more labour office",
D: "training of skilled personnel",
answer: "D. training of skilled personnel",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question23",
question: "23. Which of the following is not a development problem in Ghana? High cost of living availability of natural resources low saving capacity low technical and managed skills",
A: "**********",
B: "**********",
C: "**********",
D: "**********",
answer: "B. availability of natural resources",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question24",
question: "24. Co-operative organizations are owned and managed by",
A: "the government",
B: "the people who work in it",
C: "district assemblies",
D: "the largest shareholders",
answer: "B. the people who work in it",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question25",
question: "25. One who owns and controls a business is described as",
A: "a salesman",
B: "a broker",
C: "a partner",
D: "an entrepreneur",
answer: "D. an entrepreneur",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question26",
question: "26. The liability of sole proprietorship is unlimited. This implies that the owner",
A: "can provide as much capital as possible",
B: "enjoys all the profits.",
C: "can withdraw any amount form the bank.",
D: "can pay up business losses with his private",
answer: "D. can pay up business losses with his private",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question27",
question: "27. A nation is said to be self-reliant when",
A: "she imports all her basic needs.",
B: "she exports large quantities of cash crops.",
C: "she produces most of her basic needs.",
D: "Other counties depend on her for capital",
answer: "C. she produces most of her basic needs",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question: "28. Rule of law is based on the principle that",
A: "the president can make any law he deems fit.",
B: "nobody’s freedom can be violated",
C: "there should be checks and balances in the society,",
D: "the views of each person must be accepted.",
answer: "B. nobody's freedom can be violated",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question29",
question: "29. Which of the following are rights enjoyed by all Ghanaians?  \nI.	Protection of life and property  \nII.	Payment of taxes and levies  \nIII.	Protection of public property  \nIV.	Personal liberty",
A: "I and II only",
B: "II and IV only",
C: "l and IV only",
D: "II and IV only",
answer: "C. I and IV only",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question30",
question: "30. Which of the following are rights enjoyed by all Ghanaians?",
A: "**********",
B: "**********",
C: "**********",
D: "**********",
answer: "A. the rule of law",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question31",
question: "31. Knowing oneself enables the individual to identify his",
A: "strengths and weaknesses.",
B: "critics and adversaries.",
C: "Social status and entitlements.",
D: "Moral values and ward view",
answer: "A. strengths and weaknesses",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question32",
question: "32. When a man and a woman of the same blood relations engage in sexual relationship, they commit the offence of",
A: "rape",
B: "incest",
C: "exogamy",
D: "polyandry",
answer: "B. incest",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question33",
question: "33. Socialization is very important because it helps",
A: "in the elimination of outmoded culture.",
B: "In the survival of the society",
C: "The society to become self reliant",
D: "The development of socialist ideology",
answer: "B. In the survival of the society",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question34",
question: "34. In traditional Ghanaian societies Asafo companies functioned as",
A: "the rear-guards of chiefs",
B: "the bodyguards of chiefs",
C: "vigilant militia groups",
D: "providers of communal labour.",
answer: "C. vigilant militia groups",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question35",
question: "35. Which of the following does adolescent reproductive health aim at?  \nI.	Population issues  \nII.	Sexuality  \nIII.	Fertility regulation  \nIV.	Family life education",
A: "I, II and III only",
B: "I, III and IV only",
C: "I, II and IV only",
D: "I, III and IV only",
answer: "B. II, III and IV only",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question36",
question: "36. The Ghanaian traditional belief which undermines the stability of the family and society, and impedes national development is the belief in",
A: "ancestors",
B: "life after death",
C: "deities",
D: "witchcraft",
answer: "D. witchcraft",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question37",
question: "37. Another name for global warming is",
A: "radiation",
B: "greenhouse effect",
C: "atmospheric pressure",
D: "pollution",
answer: "B. greenhouse effect",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question38",
question: "38. All the following can contribute to rapid population growth except  desire for large families  improved medical facilities  early marriage  long period of education",
A: "**********",
B: "**********",
C: "**********",
D: "**********",
answer: "D. long period of education",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question39",
question: "39. The most immediate limitation on the rights of the citizen in any country is",
A: "existence of the police",
B: "recognition of the rights of others",
C: "criticism by the mass media.",
D: "Fear of gods and ancestral spirits.",
answer: "D. Fear of gods and ancestral spirits",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question40",
question: "40. The most important preconditions for nation-building are",
A: "foreign loans and grants.",
B: "Infrastructure facilities",
C: "Peace and stability",
D: "Skilled and unskilled labour.",
answer: "C. Peace and stability",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question41",
question: "41. Leaders are classified according to",
A: "the wealth they possess and display",
B: "The extent of the area they control",
C: "The interest they show in their followers.",
D: "How they exercise power and authority.",
answer: "D. How they exercise power and authority",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question42",
question: "42. Which of the following is not a purpose of marriage?",
A: "Acquisition of wealth",
B: "Providing companionship",
C: "Offering support for each other",
D: "Renewal of societal membership",
answer: "D. Renewal of societal membership",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question43",
question: "43. Which of the following are effects of rapid urbanization in Ghana?  \nI.	Breakdown of the extended family system  \nII.	Importation of more foreign goods  \nIII.	Increase in the fertility rate  \nIV.	Depopulation of the rural areas",
A: "l and II only",
B: "I and IV only",
C: "III and IV only",
D: "I and III only",
answer: "B. I and IV only",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question44",
question: "44. The main function of the National Board for Small Scale Industries is to",
A: "find markets for Ghanaian producers.",
B: "Procure industrial equipment for government",
C: "Assist in funding private enterprises",
D: "Control the distribution of small-scale industries.",
answer: "C. Assist in funding private enterprises",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question45",
question: "45. The most serious economic impact of the rapid spread of the HIV / AIDS pandemic on the nation is",
A: "high cost of education",
B: "loss of human resources",
C: "huge government expenditure on drugs",
D: "are precise in decision-making",
answer: "B. loss of human resources",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question46",
question: "46. The nation’s expectation of the youth in economic development is very high because they",
A: "constitute the potential labour force.",
B: "Are more knowledgeable than the elderly.",
C: "Are capable of bearing risk",
D: "Are precise in decision-making.",
answer: "A. constitute the potential labour force",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question47",
question: "47. The factors which greatly militate against the work of scientific researchers in Ghana is",
A: "apathy of government",
B: "lack of scientists.",
C: "Inadequate funding",
D: "Brain drains",
answer: "C. Inadequate funding",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question48",
question: "48. The capabilities skills and technical knowledge of a countries of a population constitute her",
A: "capital resources",
B: "productivity",
C: "technical base",
D: "human resource",
answer: "A. capital resources",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question49",
question: "49. The greatest problem hindering the growth of local industries in Ghana are",
A: "lack of skilled labour and inadequate raw materials.",
B: "limited market and lack of capital",
C: "unreliable weather and poor soil conditions.",
D: "high taxes and political interference.",
answer: "B. limited market and lack of capital",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question50",
question: "50. To sustain a business organization, the entrepreneur must",
A: "employ many of his relatives",
B: "joint a trade union",
C: "separate business account from personal accounts.",
D: "participate regularly in trade fairs.",
answer: "C. separate business account from personal accounts",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question51",
question: "51. A child develops the feeling of being inferior to others when he is often blamed and scolded he is brought up grandparents the parents die early he has no siblings",
A: "**********",
B: "**********",
C: "**********",
D: "**********",
answer: "A. he is often blamed and scolded",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question52",
question: "52. The main natural resources for human survival are",
A: "land, water and salt",
B: "land, water and air",
C: "land, air and salt",
D: "land, water and petroleum",
answer: "B. land, water and air",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question53",
question: "53. Which of the following is not a cause of the low production in the agricultural sector in Ghana?",
A: "Rural-urban migration",
B: "The extended family system",
C: "Inadequate inputs",
D: "Insufficient rainfall",
answer: "B. The extended family system",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question54",
question: "54. Caring for one’s biological children for them to become useful citizens in society is referred to as",
A: "socialization",
B: "parenthood",
C: "parenting",
D: "counselling",
answer: "B. parenthood",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question55",
question: "55. Which of the following statement is true about technology?",
A: "Research into scientific institutions",
B: "Learning of scientific principles",
C: "Discovery of scientific principles",
D: "Utilization of scientific principles",
answer: "D. Utilization of scientific principles",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question56",
question: "56. In Ghanaian traditional society, the ancestors are revered because of the belief that they",
A: "always demand sacrifices form the living",
B: "want the living to worship them",
C: "are preparing the other world for the living",
D: "are capable of blessing and protecting the living.",
answer: "D. are capable of blessing and protecting the living",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question57",
question: "57. In a business organization, records of all payments and receipts are kept in",
A: "cash book",
B: "ledger",
C: "purchase day book",
D: "sales day book",
answer: "A. cash book",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question58",
question: "58. Which of the following measures can help prevent coup d’états in Ghana?",
A: "Good governance",
B: "existence of a written constitution",
C: "Joining international organizations",
D: "Banning locally made firearms",
answer: "A. Good governance",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question59",
question: "59. Which of these is not a source of energy in the physical environment?",
A: "Sun",
B: "River",
C: "Moon",
D: "Wind",
answer: "C. Moon",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question60",
question: "60. One negative effect of trade liberalization in Ghana is",
A: "lack of foreign exchange.",
B: "closure of some local industries.",
C: "inadequate supply of raw materials",
D: "lack of entrepreneurship",
answer: "B. closure of some local industries",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},



]